## MITCHELL MILLERBERG

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished Sr. Data Analyst with over 7 years of experience in e-commerce data. Excellent reputation for creatively resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction. Dependable, self-motivated, and professional with a proven record of accomplishment in: client communications, data analytics, data modeling, manipulation, cleaning, reporting, and business intelligence. Extensive experience in multiple database languages and methodologies. Strong interpersonal skills (both verbal & written) as well as proficiency in advanced MS Office Suite applications including Excel and Access Database Management Systems. Demonstrated ability to work under pressure while meeting deadlines. Experience in managing projects and cross-functional teams through excellent relationship-building skills.

#### **SKILLS**

- Growth mindset
- MS Excel
- SQL
- Power BI
- Dashboard development
- Experience using relational databases
- Tableau/Pivot Tables
- VBA macros

- Customer first mindset
- QA Clients data questions
- Statistical data gathering
- Streamlined reporting/analytics
- Microsoft Excel
- MySQL
- Microsoft Office
- R

### • JIRA/Confluence

### **Personal Hobbies**

- Semi-professional freestyle Snowboarder
- Avid backcountry snow pow surfer
- Long-distance backpacker
- Disc golf
- Automotive car maintenance
- Bicyclist

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# SENIOR DATA ANALYST 11/2015 to 04/2023 EDGE BY ASCENTIAL

- Edge by Ascential is a market leader in e-Commerce data measurement, sales analytics, and search optimization for brand manufacturers in North America, Europe, and Asia
- Design and build ad hoc reports, and dashboards to analyze large amounts of Amazon SKU data to identify trends and find patterns within Amazon market share data
- 98% satisfaction score while solving customer service tickets
- Analyzed large amounts of data to identify trends and find patterns, signals and hidden stories within data.
- Created and automated data visualizations to present insights and tell compelling stories.
- Performed root-cause analysis on data-related system problems to recommend or execute corrective action.
- Top performer for 3 years in the catalog/operation division
- Fluent in Excel, macros, pivot tables, SQL, and other report-gathering tools
- Developed client catalogs from raw company data to track improvements in organizational efficiency and marketing strategy.

# **BIOINFORMATICS INTERN** 06/2022 to 08/2022 **UTAH STATE UNIVERSITY**, Logan, UT

- Connected over 20 genomic data sets to understand genetic relationships between species
- Researched simple-sequence repeats (SSRs) Genomic data.
- Leveraged understanding of wet-lab technology such as DNA extraction, PCR, library preparation and sequencer technology to complete quality, relevant work.
- Contributed to special projects in support of team objectives.
- Automated use of tools sequentially in pipeline.

**BIOTECHNOLOGY INTERN** 01/2020 to 01/2021 **SALT LAKE COMMUNITY COLLEGE**, South Jordan, UT

**EDUCATION** 

**Utah Valley University**, Orem, UT **Bachelor of Science**, Biotechnology, Expected in 09/2023